# Yong-Han Lin (she/her) A https://scod0401.github.io/ | ■ alberta410476@gmail.com

# **Research Interests**

My research interests lie in the fields of human-computer interaction (HCI) and ubiquitous computing (UbiComp). I am interested in 1) investigating the well-being challenges in people's daily interactions and reliance on ubiquitous technologies and 2) designing and developing tools and interventions that promote digital well-being and mental health. My research goal is to support people's use of technologies for well-being in various contexts.

#### **Education**

# National Yang-Ming Chiao-Tung University\* (NYCU)

B.S. in Computer Science

Sept. 2018 - June 2022 Hsinchu, Taiwan

- Overall GPA: 3.84/4.3 | Major GPA: 3.91/4.3 | Last 60 Credits: 4.07/4.3
- **Selected Coursework**: Data Stuctures, Database Systems, Operating Systems, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing, User Experience & Usability Evaluation, CSCW Research Summer Institute

# **Research Experience**

**NYCU Mobile Ubiquitous Interaction Lab**, Undergraduate Researcher/Research Assistant Advisor: Dr. Yung-Ju (Stanley) Chang

Sep. 2020 - Present Hsinchu, Taiwan

- Conducted a mix-method field study to understand the proposed mobile notification management features: pinning, sorting, categorizing [J.1]
- Studied users' perception of automatic, manual, and hybrid notification management modes, and the preliminary findings resulted in one poster paper at the 2023 UbiComp/ISWC conference [P.1]
- Led 3 college students and 1 graduate student to research and improve the design and features for an intelligent notification management system
- Built a notification management Android application that allows users to pin, sort, and categorize notifications, as well as predicts and presents users' preference on notifications' order by using BERT model and Flask

#### **UC Davis Collaborative and Social Computing Lab**, Research Intern

July 2022 - Oct. 2022

Advisor: Dr. Hao-Chuan Wang and Dr. Yi-Chieh (EJ) Lee

Remote

• Researched peer-review systems and human-chatbot interaction and explored how human-chatbot collaboration supports peer assessment in education scenario to enable students to generate accurate and fair feedback

#### **Polytechnique Montreal Human-Centered Design Lab**, Research Intern

June 2021 – Jan. 2022

Advisor: Dr. Jinghui Cheng

Remote

• Conducted a qualitative content analysis and a statistical analysis to understand the usage, purposes, and impacts of visual artifacts in GitHub issue tracker system, the findings resulted in a paper at the 2022 EASE conference [C.1]

# **Peer-Reviewed Publications**

(\* indicates equal contribution)

[J.1] "Pinning, Sorting, and Categorizing Notifications: A Mixed-methods Usage and Experience Study of Mobile Notification-management Features" [In submission to ACM IMWUT '24]

Yong-Han Lin, Li-Ting Su, Uei-Dar Chen, Yi-Chi Lee, Peng-Jui Wang, Yung-Ju Chang.

[P.1] "Automatic, Manual, or Hybrid? A Preliminary Investigation of Users' Perception of Features for Supporting Notification Management" [paper]

**Yong-Han Lin**, Li-Ting Su, Uei-Dar Chen, Peng-Jui Wang, Yi-Chi Lee, Yung-Ju Chang. In *Adjunct Proceedings of the 2023 ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing & the 2023 ACM International Symposium on Wearable Computing (UbiComp/ISWC '23)*, pp. 98-102.

<sup>\*</sup>Former name: National Chiao Tung University (NCTU)

# [C.2] "Multiple Device Users' Actual and Ideal Cross-device Usage for Multi-Stage Notification-Interactions: An ESM Study Addressing the Usage Gap and Impacts of Device Context" [paper]

Fang-Ching Tseng, Zih-Yun Chiou, Ho-Hsuan Chuang, Li-Ting Su, **Yong-Han Lin**, Yu-Rou Lin, Yi-Chi Lee, Peng-Jui Wang, Uei-Dar Chen, Yung-Ju Chang. In *Proceedings of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems* **(CHI '23)**, pp. 1-15.

# [C.1] "Understanding the Characteristics of Visual Contents in Open Source Issue Discussions" [paper][video]

Vishakha Agrawal\*, **Yong-Han Lin\***, Jinghui Cheng. In *Proceedings of the 26th International Conference on Evaluation and Assessment in Software Engineering* **(EASE '22)**, pp. 249-254.

# **Teaching Experience**

# **Teaching Assistant**

NYCU CS 1270: Introduction to Database Systems (Spring 2022)

Instructor: Dr. Yi-Ju Tseng

#### **Course Assistant**

NYCU General Education: Critical and Creative Thinking (Spring 2021)

Instructor: Dr. Jonathon Hricko

#### **Honors and Awards**

# Taiwan National Science and Technology Council Research Grant Award (Fall 2021)

Received a grant for doing research on studying users' perception of different notification management methods

# Polytechnique Montreal Research Internship Scholarship (Summer 2021)

Paid for being a research intern during the summer

#### **Volunteer and Leadership**

# **Student Volunteer**

CHI 2023, Hamburg

Provided support for paper session, hybrid Zoom meeting, and exhibit hall

CSCW 2022, Virtual

Monitored paper presentation video on YouTube livestream, and provided quick responses in GatherTown

#### **Team Leader in Public Relation**

Mei-Chu Hackathon 2020

Led a team of 6 students to contact corporate sponsorship and received 40K+ USD from Google, Amazon, etc

# Other Work Experience

# **Software Engineering Intern**

Xaduro Inc. (travel tech startup)

Jan. 2021 – June 2021 Taipei, Taiwan

- Collaborated with the engineering team to develop a travel agency system that allows 1K+ users by using MySQL, PHP, and JavaScript
- Optimized the hotel reservation system by fixing 80% of the usability issues detected from Google Search Console

### Skills

Programming Languages: Python, JavaScript, R, Java, C++/C, SQL, PHP, HTML, CSS

Tools: Android, Git, Firebase, Flask, Linux, LTFX